Samantha Sitarek

Data Analyst | Retail Financial Analyst | Business Analyst



I love how data is its own language, one that can be leveraged to provide insight on how to improve nearly anything, but you must know how to interpret the language if you are to tell the data's story. "Numbers have an important story to tell. They rely on you to give them a clear and convincing voice" – Stephen Few, data visualization expert

SKILLS

Tableau | Power BI | SQL (PostgreSQL, Joins) | Python | EDA | ETL | Microsoft PowerPoint, Word, Excel (PivotTables, VLOOKUP) | JIRA P&L and KPI Analysis | EQ | Business Acumen | Workplace Conflict Management | Strong Work Ethic | Integrity First | Attention to Detail

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Xsolis | Business Analyst | June 2022 - Present

An Al-driven technology company with a mission to foster payer-provider collaboration across a connected network through real-time transparency by providing purpose-built solutions, accelerating data-driven decision making, addressing revenue challenges, and maximizing the clinical expertise to support each client's most valuable resource; their people.

- Work with internal cross functional teams to provide accurate communication to clients and client facing teams
- Communicate complex, technical principles and issues to non-technical audiences (up to and including C-suite executives)
- Partner with Account Managers, Nurse Optimization Consultant, and Client Relationship Executives during virtual client calls to drive adoption and optimal use by assisting in navigation and knowledge of reports, providing insight to the data, and facilitate resolution of ad-hoc client requests to build client relationships
- Provide Net Profit Revenue calculations for both payer and provider clients
- Aid in Business Review development by analyzing client metric data to identify areas of success and areas of improvement, translate the data's story and represent it visually for client presentation.

Courage Music Division at Courage Capital Management | Data Analyst | September 2021 - November 2022

Courage Music was formed by senior music executives to provide a better solution for sellers to monetize music rights. Courage Music is a long-term investor supporting select music publishers, record labels, recording artists and songwriters. This position currently utilizes Excel, SQL, and Tableau the most.

- Analyze music catalog data and prepare data for ingestion
- Filter, clean, maintain, and refine music catalog metadata
- Support catalog optimization strategies and initiatives
- Identify, analyze, and interpret trends or patterns in complex data sets using analytical techniques

Nashville Software School | Data Analytics Apprentice | May 2021 - August 2021

Data Analytics Bootcamp program which provides knowledge of how to apply statistical reasoning through hands-on training in Excel, Python, SQL, Tableau, and Power BI. The program develops an understanding of Exploratory Data Analysis, Analytics Workflow, and Agile Project Management.

- ♦ Nashville City Cemetery | Excel Project
 - > Leveraged lessons in Excel to provide insights for the data provided and visualizations for marketing.
- ❖ Lahman Baseball | SQL Project
 - Leveraged lessons in SQL and worked in a team environment to execute SQL queries that would answer several questions regarding the 27 tables provided in the dataset.
- Historical Markers by Zipcode | Python, Jupyter Project
 - Leveraged lessons in Python via Jupyter Notebooks to explore the Historical Markers dataset and the Zipcodes dataset (both found on data.nashville.gov) together and created visualizations in the geospatial environment.
- ♦ <u>Higher Education Advisory Tool</u> | Python, Beautiful Soup, Tableau Capstone Project
 - ➤ Leveraged lessons in Python, Web Scraping, and Tableau to create a dashboard to help a student and their advisor visualize the path for success. I utilized Beautiful Soup to obtain each school's offered degree/certificate paths, requirements of the programs, courses and their descriptions.

A company that partners with name brand retailers to provide customers access to products they want and need but are unable to get from the retail store. Lease-to-own model allows customers to shop for their desired purchase and utilize the no-credit-needed program with flexible payments and monthly credit reporting.

Retail Finance & Business Analyst/District Manager | December 2019 - February 2021

- Utilized KPIs, P&Ls, and Pencils and Projections to forecast data-driven sales plans for while leading with an emphasis on the power of teamwork to reach company metrics
- Managed hours, overtime, training, and staffing of over 40 employees in 18 locations using ADP (Automatic Data Processing)
- Continued to utilize my 8-level training program to lead the accelerated development of team members, resulting in 14 successful promoted employees
- Performed business analysis functions and improved host-store relationships with all 6 vendors across 18 locations

Retail Finance & Business Analyst/Store Manager | July 2016 - December 2019

- Proactively communicate critical data and information to senior management along with real-time response initiatives
- Improved profit-based metrics such as year-over-year sales growth, total revenue, average ticket price, and net profit margin
- Created a comprehensive 8-level training program that led to accelerated development of team members, resulting in 4 successful promoted employees
- Earned the 2018 Perform to Win Award

Retail Analyst | May 2016 - July 2016

- Understand and use tools to document decisions, action items, purchases, and contracts
- Build strong client relationships and interpersonal skills
- Effectively prioritize workload to meet deadlines and work objectives

MILITARY EXPERIENCE

NJ Air National Guard | Aerospace Propulsion Apprentice | September 2009 - April 2014

I was honored to be able to serve and deploy. My experience with the military has been a key part of who I am today. I have taken so much with me from these years and am grateful for the experience.

- The 3 core values that still hold true to me today: Integrity First, Service Before Self, Excellence In All We Do
- Attention to detail is crucial to getting something right
- Practice doesn't make perfect, practice makes permanent
- Decisions you make effect more than just you, it's important to see the bigger picture
- You are not a one man show, you fail and succeed as a team

EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATIONS

Nashville Software School | August 2021

Data Analytics Bootcamp Certification

COMMUNITY INVOLVEMENT AND INTERESTS

Performing Arts

- Eden School of Dance | Ballet, Pointe, Tap, Jazz, Company
- Dance, Inc. | Ballet, Pointe, Tap, Jazz, Company, Modern, Hip-Hop
- Ann A. Mullen Middle School | Trumpet, Flute, Piccolo, Clarinet, Percussion, Choir
- Timber Creek Regional High School | Flute, Piccolo, Bassoon, Choir, Marching Band, Indoor Color Guard

Clubs

Timber Creek Regional High School | Italian Club, Vocal Club, World of Difference, Mock Trial, Theater

Volunteer Experience

- Eden School of Dance | Student Teacher
- Timber Creek Regional High School | Color Guard Instructor